

CONTACT

- (+91) 9035841455
- □ abhi03.11sharma@gmail.com
- in AK-LinkedIn
- AK-Github
- **AK-Portfolio**

SKILLS

SAS, SQL, Python, Git

Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn

Data Integration, Prep, EDA, Data Cleaning, Visualization, Feature Engineering, e-DWH, Meta & Statistical Analysis

Regression, Classification, Clustering, Decision Trees, Random forest

Machine Learning Techniques

SAS DI, IRM, RFW, VA, EG SAS Risk Stratum, Tableau

Process Automation
Unix, Shell & Batch Scripting

ABHISHEK KUMAR

Data Analyst / SDE

I have 5.0 years of experience in Business Intelligence & Data Science Solutions as Data Analyst / Developer in BFSI domain. I hold expertise in Data Analysis, Data Integration & Prep, Visualization, ETL, DWH, Dashboards & Process Automation with SAS, SQL & Python.

Possess understanding of ML Algorithm for Prediction & Classification use-cases. Performed **Statistical Analysis**, **EDA**, **Feature Engineering**, **Model Selection**, **Building & Evaluation** with **Pandas**, **Seaborn**, **Matplotlib** & **Scikit-learn**.

Self-Motivated to learn & explore new skills and technlogies as well as accountable for my tasks. I can work in a team or independently. Currently pursuing **PG Diploma** in **Machine Learning & AI, IIIT-B.**

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2019 – Present / Senior Software Engineer / SAS R&D

- Working as a Developer & Analyst to implement new features for COREP & FINREP (Reports) in SAS Regulatory and Reporting Solutions for Credit Risk Management.
- Design and Development of Automated Validation
 Framework to improve the dev-test pipeline.

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019 / Senior Analyst / Citigroup, India

- Analysed and processed credit portfolios to generate insights with regular & adhoc reports.
- Took critical initiatives to **re-design and develop** the process.

Jul 2016 - Mar 2019 / Associate Consultant / Capgemini, India

- Implemented e-DWH and KPIs for Insurance client.
- Developed **Modular, Dynamic, Data-driven and Efficient** codes through Base SAS, SAS/SQL, SAS Macros & Functions.
- Gathered requirement and designed one of the ETL layer.
- Experience in **Data Quality & Tableau Visualizations**.

CERTIFICATIONS

2019 / SAS Certified Data Integration Developer 2018 / SAS Certified Advanced SAS Developer 2018 / SAS Certified Base SAS Developer

EDUCATION

IIIT-Bangalore , UpGrad PGD, Machine Learning & Al, 2021

PES Institute of Technology B.E, Information Science, 2016

Ekalavya Educational Complex Higher Secondary, 2011

St. Karen's High School Secondary School, 2009

TRAININGS

Python for Data Science, 2020 Multiple SAS Tech, 2017-2020

AWARDS

VCR Award, 2021 @ SAS R&D VCR Award, 2020 @ SAS R&D Star Award, 2018 @ CapG

ACCOMPLISHMENT

Tech-Expo @ SAS R&D Gold-Badges @ Hackerrank Samurai @ SASensei

INTERESTS

Cricket
Problem Solving
Machine Learning

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi

PROJECTS

Feb 2020 - Present / SAS® Regulatory Content for EBA Taxos

- Analysis and Development of Reports & ETL Framework to incorporate EBA Taxonomies for European Union banks.
- Developed pipeline to track Data Validation Failures & QC.
- SAS, SQL, Macros, Python, IRM, RFW, GIT, ETL, Analysis.

Aug 2019 - Jan 2020 / SAS® Solution for Regulatory Capital

- Implemented the **Minimum Loss Coverage** IRB Shortfall amt for loans in European banks covering **Credit Risk** Management.
- Rebuilding the solution on top of SAS Risk Stratum platform.
- SAS, SQL, Macros, IRM, Python, SAS VA, Risk Stratum.

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019/ MIS Reporting & Framework

- Designed & Developed an Automated Framework for Daily,
 Weekly and Monthly Campaign and Portfolio Reports.
- Design and development of reports Regular and Adhoc.
- SAS, SQL, Macros, Python, Shell, EG, ETL, DB, Data Analysis.

Jul 2016 - Mar 2019 / Anabel for Baloise Insurance

- An Enterprise Datawarehouse (e-DWH) based on SAS DDS
 Model for Insurance to achieve data unification.
- Developed SAS Programs, DI & Dataflux jobs for Integration, Cleansing, Standardization and Loading of data (ETL).
- **Dashboard** to visualize **Customer Portfolio** across products.
- SAS, SAS/SQL, Macros, SAS-DI, DataFlux, Tableau, DB, ETL.

Mini-Projects @ Github

Jan 2021 / Telecom Churn Prediction

• This project predicts customers at high risk of churn.

Oct 2020 / Shared Bike Demand Prediction

 This project predicts the bike demand using multiple linear regression model.

Oct 2020 / Lending Club Credit Default Analysis

 The Data Analysis is performed on customer data of Lending Club to understand the driver features of loan default.

Sep 2020 / Investment Analysis

• The EDA is performed to understand the Global Investment trends and provide investment suggestions to Spark Funds.